welcome back to another shotcut video
欢迎回到另一个截图视频
editing tutorial in this video we're
编辑教程在这段视频中我们
gonna spend a lot more time on using the
将花费更多的时间来使用
timeline editing our video we're
时间线编辑我们的视频
learning about lots of different tools
了解许多不同的工具
to do that so to get started we'll just
要做到这一点 开始之前 我们只需
type in a project name and hit start and
键入项目名称 然后按Start和
then if again like like in the last
那么如果再像上次一样
video if yours doesn't look exactly the
如果你的视频看起来不太像
same way we can click on settings and or
同样 我们可以单击设置和/或
click on View and go to layout and
点击查看并转到布局 然后
choose from some of these different
从这些不同的选项中选择一些
layouts but the most important thing is
布局 但最重要的是
to have this playlists active so you
将此播放列表激活 以便您
might have filters you can go down here
可能有过滤器 你可以在这里找到
and click on playlists
并点击播放列表
if playlist doesn't appear you can click
如果没有显示播放列表 您可以点击
on playlist and it'll bring it up so
在播放列表上 它会把它带到
once we have playlists then we can
一旦我们有了播放列表 我们就可以
actually go to our video clips so I have
实际上去我们的视频剪辑 所以我有
some clips selected here I just hit hold
这里选择了一些剪辑 我刚按下保持键
down the shift key and select multiple
按住Shift键并选择多个
clips and then left click and drag and
剪辑 然后左键单击并拖动
drop them in and that it starts playing
把它们放进去 它就开始播放了
so we have all these clips in here that
所以我们在这里有所有的剪辑
I just brought in from my computer
我刚从我的电脑里拿来
another way to bring in clips is to just
引入剪辑的另一种方法是
go to open and then you can select
转到打开 然后您可以选择
multiple clips or individual clips and
多个剪辑或单个剪辑和
it will add them here as well this one's
它将把它们加到这里 这一个也是
already I already brought it in once and
我已经带了一次了
so if we double click on one of these in
因此 如果我们双击其中一个
the playlist it shows us what we're
它的播放列表向我们展示了我们是什么
looking at as our source our project is
将我们的项目视为我们的来源
not active yet there's nothing in our
不活跃 但在我们的
actual project and down here there's
实际的项目 在这里有
that there's also timeline and keyframes
还有时间线和关键帧
and I just want to mention if you're on
我只想说如果你在
keyframes and you try and drag a video
关键帧 然后尝试拖动一段视频
down it's not gonna go down it's not
它不会掉下去的 不会掉下来的
gonna go into your project because you
进入你的项目是因为你
don't have any project you have to go to
没有任何你必须去做的项目
Timeline and then you can drag it in and
时间线 然后你可以把它拖进去
then you'll actually have this video
然后你就会看到这段视频
track so right now I just brought this
所以现在我带来了这个
video in here and we can bring it right
视频在这里 我们可以把它带到正确的地方
to the beginning if I want to have a
从头开始 如果我想要
different video clip like this one here
不同的视频剪辑 就像这里的
I can drag it down and now I have a gap
我可以把它拉下来 现在我有了一个缺口
in there as well and if I want to bring
在那里 如果我想把
in this is like a very long video it's
就像是一段很长的视频
one minute and 29 seconds I'm not very
1分29秒我不是很
long but it's a if I bring it down it's
很长 但如果我把它弄下来 那就是
going to take up quite a bit of space on
将会占用相当大的空间
my timeline and I can zoom out and see
我和我的时间线可以缩小看到
compared to these first two this one's
与前两个相比 这个是
pretty long which is fine so I can
很长时间 这很好 所以我可以
left-click and move these around but
左键点击并移动这些 但是
maybe I only want a small portion of
也许我只想要一小部分
this
这
video there's a couple ways to get just
视频有几种方法可以让你
a portion so I can find the part that I
这样我就能找到我想要的那部分
want maybe this part where he's
可能想要他在的这一段
hammering on this piece of iron we just
敲打着这块铁 我们只是
get to play head to that portion and if
可以打到那个部分的头 如果
we hover over this tool we can see what
我们将鼠标悬停在这个工具上 就可以看到
it's called this tool is called split at
这个工具叫做Split at
playhead if we can click it and it will
播放头 如果我们可以点击它 它会
split the video right where the playhead
将视频分割到播放头的位置
was now I have two video clips this one
现在我有两个视频剪辑这一个
and this one if I hit play they're gonna
而这一次如果我按下Play他们就会
seamlessly go right next to each other
无缝地紧挨着彼此
because it's even though there are two
因为即使有两个
video clips you know we split it so it's
视频剪辑你知道我们把它分了 所以它
supposed to be there if we click this
如果我们点击这个 就应该在那里
first one I hit the Delete key it'll go
第一个我按Delete键 它就会响
away and then we can come to the portion
走了 然后我们就可以到那部分了
maybe we only want to have the hammering
也许我们只想要锤子
happen during this you know about this
发生在这期间 你知道这件事
length we hit the split again select the
我们再次命中拆分的长度选择
second part of the video by left
视频的第二部分左边
clicking on it and hitting the Delete
点击它 然后点击Delete
key on the keyboard and now we just have
键盘上的按键 现在我们只有
a nice short video clip of just
一个不错的短片短片
hammering on this piece of steel I can
敲打这块钢铁 我能
left-click and drag it and bring it
左键单击并拖动它 然后将其带到
closer into my project actually I'm
更接近我的项目实际上我是
gonna bring it away for one set because
我要把它带走一盘 因为
I want to show you another way if I want
如果我想的话 我想给你看另一条路
to have this video clip of this horn
有这个号角的视频剪辑
looks like a Powderhorn
看起来像是一只鲍德霍恩
we can left-click here and we can shrink
我们可以左键点击这里 我们可以缩小
this down as well so we hover to the end
这也落下了 所以我们盘旋到了尽头
of the video clip hold down left click
在视频剪辑中按住左键点击
and we can make that video shorter so
我们可以让视频变得更短 这样
now I have a couple short clips here
现在我这里有几个短片
they even publish it I made even a
他们甚至发表了我甚至做了一个
little bit shorter than that but I want
比那个短一点 但我想
to show you another way we can do so
向你展示我们可以做到的另一种方式
this one here if we go back to our
如果我们回到我们的
source on this one we see now we're
我们现在看到的这个消息的来源是
playing and it's not moving on our
玩着 它不会在我们的
timeline because we're looking at our
时间线因为我们看到的是我们的
source but if I want to get just this
来源 但如果我只想要这个
portion of the fire I can actually come
我能来的火种的一部分
over here and I can click these little
在这里 我可以点击这些小东西
triangles now I can select just a small
三角形现在我可以只选择一个小的
portion of video here and I can drag it
视频的一部分在这里 我可以拖动它
down so maybe it's a teeny tiny portion
所以可能只是很小的一部分
I can left-click and drag and now it
我可以左键单击并拖动 现在它
brings in just this little sliver of
只带来了这一小块
video it doesn't bring in the whole one
它不会带来完整的视频
minute and 29 seconds worth it just
一分29秒值得一试
brings in this little tiny portion right
带来这一小部分的权利
here
这里
so we can play that and see what looks
所以我们可以播放它 看看它看起来像什么
like another good way to do that is go
另一个很好的方法就是去
back to the source we can change if we
回到源头 我们可以改变 如果我们
want the out point instead of dragging
想要出点而不是拖拽
this triangle we can just go to that
这个三角形 我们可以直接去那个
portion and hit the O key on the
部分并按下O键
keyboard and that selects the out point
键盘并选择OUT点
we can go to this part and select the I
我们可以转到此部分并选择i
key on the keyboard I select the end
键盘上的键我选择结束
point so while that's playing we can
点 所以在播放的同时 我们可以
press I then press o on the keyboard and
按I键 然后按键盘上的O键 然后
now we've got a tiny little sliver of
现在我们得到了一小块
video that we can use so play with that
我们可以使用的视频 所以可以使用它进行播放
it's a really really good tool and it's
这是一个非常非常好的工具 而且
similar functionality you'll find in
类似的功能 您可以在
lots of video editing software if we
很多视频编辑软件 如果我们
want to get rid of a clip again we
想要再次摆脱一个剪辑 我们
left-click it'll be selected in red we
左键单击它将被选中为红色WE
have the Delete key and it goes away but
按Delete键 它就会消失 但
there's a gap now there's a black gap
有一个缺口 现在有一个黑色的缺口
that'll play this black nothingness and
将扮演这个黑色的虚无和
then it jumps to the next part of the
然后 它跳到
video so if I hit control Z it'll undo
视频 所以如果我按下Ctrl Z 它就会撤销
that change will come back you can also
这种变化会回来的 你也可以
go to edit undo to bring it back but if
转到编辑撤消以将其恢复 但如果
I want this clip to disappear and I want
我想让这段视频消失 我想
the gap to not be there I want this
不在那里的差距我想要这个
video to just kind of shrink up and
视频变得有点缩水了
appear right there let me zoom in a
出现在那里 让我放大一个
little bit so we can see that more we
一点 这样我们就能看到更多我们
could actually just click the cut over
实际上只需点击切换
here and we'll cut that clip out and
在这里 我们会把那段剪辑剪下来
then everything just shrinks up right to
然后一切都会缩小到
her it was going to be before and now
她以前和现在都会是这样
that video clip is now saved in our
该视频剪辑现在保存在我们的
clipboard so if I want to we come over
剪贴板所以如果我想我们就过来
here to the playhead I can hit the paste
在这里我可以把球打到头球
icon and now that video that I cut out
图标 现在我剪下的视频
is gonna be pasted here at the end so if
会在最后贴在这里 所以如果
I want to move this clip to the end
我想把这段视频移到最后
without creating a gap I mean I could
在不制造差距的情况下 我的意思是我可以
just left-click and move it but now
只需左键单击并移动它 但现在
there's a gap there so if I want to move
那里有个缺口 所以如果我想搬家
it to the end without creating a gap I
在不留空隙的情况下一直到最后
had the cut I select it first hit cut
让我先选择切割 然后点击切割
and then go to how the playhead to go to
然后去怎么样的播放头去
wherever I want it to paste it which
我想把它贴在哪里都行
will lead to the end and hit paste now
将通向末尾并点击立即粘贴
I've effectively moved that to the end
我有效地把这件事推到了最后
without creating any gaps does that make
在不制造任何间隙的情况下
sense maybe I want this portion over
感觉也许我想要结束这一部分
here I can play it see what this looks
在这里我可以播放它 看看这看起来是什么样子
like
喜欢
I want this portion of the video to play
我希望播放视频的这一部分
multiple times well what I can do is hit
很多次 我所能做的就是击中
the copy so I copy
复印件 所以我复印
now that's copied to the
现在 它被复制到
bored and now I can paste it I can go to
无聊了 现在我可以粘贴了 我可以去
the end and hit paste and it paste this
结束并点击粘贴 然后粘贴此内容
video so it's still over here but it's
视频 所以它还在这里 但它
also over here and I can just keep
也在这里 我可以继续
hitting paste a couple times really so i
敲击粘贴几次真的让我
wherever the playhead is is where it
播放头在哪里 它就在哪里
will paste it in so if i want this to be
我会把它粘贴进去 所以如果我想让它
between these two i hit paste and it
在这两个之间 我点击了粘贴和它
appears between those two so if i wanted
出现在这两者之间 所以如果我想
to here i come right to here and hit
到了这里 我直接来到这里 击打
paste and now it appears there so now we
粘贴 现在它出现在那里 所以现在我们
have kind of this fire happening in
有没有发生过这样的火灾
between every little clip what else
在每一个小片段之间还有什么
snapping do we talk about snapping so if
抓拍我们谈到抓拍了吗？所以如果
we want to snap to the playhead I have
我们想要抓住我的玩具头
snapping enabled right now if I take it
如果我按下 立即启用捕捉
off it's this little magnet magnet icon
就是这个小小的磁铁图标
if I have that off then it's gonna be a
如果我把它脱了 那将是一场
little bit harder for me if I try and
对我来说有点难 如果我试着
drag this clip right up here I'm always
把这段视频拖上来 我一直都在
gonna have a little bit of like a little
会有一点像是有点
yellow gap in there I'm not gonna get
在那里的黄色缺口 我不会得到
right to it because it's kind of hard
直截了当 因为这有点难
without snapping but what snapping does
没有捕捉 但捕捉的作用是什么
is it makes it so that we always snap
它是不是让我们总是抓狂？
right to the clip so what kind of pauses
直奔视频片段 那么什么样的停顿呢？
and lets it snap to a clip or to the
并让它捕捉到剪辑或
playhead if I want this to snap to the
PlayHead如果我想让它捕捉到
playhead it'll also kind of pause a
Playhead它还会暂停一段时间
little bit and let me snap right to the
一点点 让我直截了当地
playhead if I have a gap and I want to
如果我有差距 我想要
move a video in and the gap is not large
移入一段视频 差距并不大
enough I can't get the video in there so
够了 我不能把视频放进去 所以
sometimes you'll be like this video will
有时你会像这段视频一样
fit there won't it and you're wondering
适合那里 不是吗 你在想
why it won't go well it's because you
为什么不会顺利 是因为你
don't have a big enough space that's
没有足够大的空间
only when you're moving video from
仅当您从
within the timeline if you're bringing
在时间线内 如果你要带
in video from up here like this one with
在上面的视频中 就像这一段
the horn if I drag this down it's
喇叭如果我把它往下拉
usually it gives me a warning oh I guess
通常它会给我一个警告 哦 我想
maybe it'll do it there but if I have it
也许它会在那里做 但如果我有它
selected here and I drag it down it's
在这里被选中 然后我把它拖下来
gonna say overwrite so it's gonna say
会说覆盖 所以它会说
warning this is like where by dragging
警告：这就像是通过拖动
this clip in if you drag it in right
如果你把它拖到右边 这个夹子就放进去
here now you're gonna overwrite
现在你要改写
everything that's we'll kind of shaded
一切都会被我们遮盖住
white here which would mean this all
这里是白色的 这意味着这一切
these video clips will be gone and it'll
这些视频剪辑将会消失 它将
cut into this one and cut into this ones
切开这个 切开这个
that make sense let's give it a try so
有道理 让我们试一试吧 所以
we bring it down and we bring it there
我们把它带下来 然后把它带到那里
now this video clip is here and
现在这段视频剪辑在这里
everything else that was there is now
以前的一切现在都在那里了
gone so just be aware of that when
消失了 所以当你意识到这一点时
you're bringing in video clips it's good
你带来了视频剪辑 这很好
to bring them into like a blank space
把他们带进一个空白的空间
over the back to my source it's good to
回到我的消息来源 这是件好事
bring them into the blank space at the
把他们带到空白处
end of yours if you're worried about
如果你担心的是
over writing and it'll tell you if
写完了 它会告诉你
you're gonna overwrite it or not so I
你要不要覆盖它 所以我
think that's all we're gonna do in this
你觉得这就是我们要做的
one if ever you're wondering what
如果你想知道什么的话
something does you can hover over and
一些你可以悬停在上面的东西
see what these different things do and
看看这些不同的东西有什么作用
so like the ripple delete does kind of
所以就像涟漪删除一样
similar to what we're talking about is
与我们正在讨论的内容类似的是
where it gets rid of it and then
在那里它摆脱了它 然后
everything sucks in so it's the same as
一切都被吸进去了 所以它是一样的
doing kept so if you click on a clip and
如果你点击一个剪辑并保持这种状态
then hit ripple delete it deletes it and
然后点击涟漪删除它删除它并
sucks in everything without leaving an
吸收一切 而不会留下
empty gap here so yeah and then the
空隙在这里 所以是的 然后是
scrub this is this enabled scrubbing so
擦除这是启用的擦除 因此
that when you move a video clip you can
当你移动视频剪辑时 你可以
hear what's happening with it at the
听到它在那里发生了什么
same time that's kind of I don't really
与此同时 我真的不是很想
use that feature so I think I'm gonna
使用这个功能 所以我想我要
end this video here go ahead and play
在此结束此视频 继续播放
with you know resizing your your
你知道 调整你的
timeline play with some of these cut
时间线播放其中一些剪辑
copy and paste tools you can also use
还可以使用复制和粘贴工具
the keyboard shortcuts control X to cut
键盘快捷键控制要剪切的X
ctrl C to copy and ctrl V to paste go
按Ctrl C进行复制 按Ctrl V进行粘贴
ahead and play with some of those play
继续玩其中的一些游戏
with adding in different clips make sure
通过添加不同的剪辑 确保
you know the difference between your
你知道你和你的朋友
source and your project and on your
源代码和您的项目 并在您的
source play with some of the in and out
源码播放一些进进出出的
of selecting just a certain portion so
只选择特定的部分 所以
you don't have to come down here and you
你不必下来这里 然后你
know cut it out by splitting it playhead
知道通过分裂它的播放头来切断它
all that and then be aware too you can
所有这些 然后意识到你也可以
do all these edits instead of using
执行所有这些编辑操作 而不是使用
these icons you can click on edit up top
你可以点击上面的这些图标进行编辑
and we also have cut copy paste undo
我们也有剪切复制粘贴撤消功能
redo I guess it's not all of them up
重做 我猜不是所有人都跳起来了
there but we have some of those tools
但我们有一些这样的工具
available at the top thank you for
在顶部可用感谢您
watching go ahead and like comment
观看畅所欲言并点赞评论
subscribe leave your questions below and
订阅请在下面留下您的问题并
I'll catch you in the next video
我会在下一个视频中看到你